Suchithra S

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

■ suchisunsan.s@gmail.com
 □ 8848499282
 Palakkad, Kerala, India

in linkedin.com/in/suchithrashiju

SUMMARY

Software Developer with 8+ years of experience in developing applications using PHP and PHP Frameworks . Currently working with Angular and Node JS Projects. I succeed to grow my programming skills in different areas. I participate in apps based on products and projects. Designing, developing, unit testing, troubleshooting and debugging of the applications. Team leading and Project Management.

SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Angular
- Javascript, Typescript, Node JS
- Windows, Ubuntu
- PHP, CakePHP, Zend, Codeigniter, Codeigniter Blade, Laravel

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Programmer

Winds Business Solutions - Palakkad - India Jun 2020 - Present

- Developed Websites and Web Applications
- Developed E commerce Website using Angular Cosmo, DSR, Vansales & Premier Tissues
- Collaborating with other team members to developing web applications(Products) using Angular and Node.JS – Lytty , Loyalty App

Sofware Developer

G3 Interactive - Palakkad - India Feb 2019 - Feb 2020

- Developed website and web application using PHP(Codelgniter / CODEIGNITER Blade) & MySQL. The Projects likes Yourmob, Imagelibrary, TVE Services, etc
- Collaborating with other team members to developing web applications using LARAVEL Immigration Guru, Hybuilt, Tablogs etc
- Worked as a Dedicated developer in .NET(windows app) & SQL Server. The Projects likes Aeropower, File processor.Norditech etc
- Collaborating with other team members to developing web applications using Wordpress Demurrage etc
- TVE Web Application Management and Crew Leader.

Programmer

WindOnline Pvt Ltd • Palakkad • India Nov 2014 - Feb 2019

- Developed more than 10 website and Ecommerce website using PHP(Codelgniter/CakePHP) & MySQL.
 The Projects likes Amrita Medical Sceince, Ayurvedamanzil, Sreerama Industries, Lead, Shivanies, Jasmine Boutique, Twinbirds, Windsbsolutions etc
- Collaborating with other team members to developing web applications using PHP Zend Framework Retailbean Lite, Lytty etc

Java/.Net Project Developer

Mazenet Solutions/Bessel Infotech Solutions Pvt Ltd Apr 2012 - Oct 2014

- Programming Tutor
- Developed Engineering and Degree Academic Projects
- Managed more than 15 Projects through these programming languages Java, JSP,. Net Framework, PHP etc.

Programming Faculty

G-Tec Computer Education • Palakkad • India May 2011 - Mar 2012

• Programming Tutor

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree in Computer Application
Bharathiar University Tamilnadu Mar 2015 - Mar 2017

Diploma in Computer Engineering IPT&GPC Shornur, Kerala Mar 2008 - Mar 2011

Class 12

GHSS Kottayi May 2006 - May 2008 Commerce With Computer Application

LANGUAGES

English	Tamil	
Malayalam		

DECLARATION

I hereby affirm that the information provided by me is accurate and true to the best of my knowledge.

Palakkad Suchithra.S